<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://leomaglanoc.github.io/feed/blogs.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://leomaglanoc.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2026-01-01T11:18:52+00:00</updated><id>https://leomaglanoc.github.io/feed/blogs.xml</id><title type="html">blank | Blogs</title><subtitle>Leonardo Maglanoc&apos;s personal website on robotics, AI, and humanoid robots. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">AI Coding Agent Case Study: Gaming Library</title><link href="https://leomaglanoc.github.io/blog/AI-coding-agent-case-study/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AI Coding Agent Case Study: Gaming Library"/><published>2025-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://leomaglanoc.github.io/blog/AI-coding-agent-case-study</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://leomaglanoc.github.io/blog/AI-coding-agent-case-study/"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been experimenting with Codex, OpenAI’s coding agent (Codex 5.2). Below are some games I ‘vibecoded’ in less than an hour without writing a single code line and having any previous experience with game programming. I additionally used ChatGPT to brainstorm on the design and the mechanics of the game. These games may not be 100% functional, but I’m amazed by the progress and capabilities of generative, agentic AI, even though they have some limitations too.</p> <ul> <li><a href="/assets/interactive/flappy/index.html">Flappy Bird</a></li> <li><a href="/assets/interactive/race/index.html">Top Down Racing Game</a></li> <li><a href="/assets/interactive/robot-runner/index.html">Jump and Run Sidescroller</a></li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blogpost"/><category term="game"/><category term="canvas"/><category term="javascript"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been experimenting with Codex, OpenAI’s coding agent (Codex 5.2). Below are some games I ‘vibecoded’ in less than an hour without writing a single code line and having any previous experience with game programming. I additionally used ChatGPT to brainstorm on the design and the mechanics of the game. These games may not be 100% functional, but I’m amazed by the progress and capabilities of generative, agentic AI, even though they have some limitations too.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Research Goals</title><link href="https://leomaglanoc.github.io/blog/research-goals/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Research Goals"/><published>2025-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://leomaglanoc.github.io/blog/research-goals</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://leomaglanoc.github.io/blog/research-goals/"><![CDATA[ <p>My ultimate dream is to enable safe and reliable humanoid autonomy in human environments. I want to achieve this by tackling the following subproblems:</p> <ul> <li>Safety and reliability guarantees with safe control methods</li> <li>Unify manipulation and locomotion in one safe loco-manipulation framework</li> <li>Semantic reasoning with foundation models</li> <li>Testing safe humanoids in real-world industrial and domestic use cases.</li> </ul> <p>My first goal is to provide reliability guarantees, for example, through the formal verification of the safety and functionality of robotics systems. Ensuring safe robot autonomy in human environments is a critical issue, as failures such as collisions with humans would be catastrophic and must be prevented if we want to deploy robots in these environments.</p> <p>My second goal is to extend the problem setting from humanoid manipulation to loco-manipulation. Why? Because most real tasks require mobility of the autonomous system. And because locomotion and manipulation are inherently a coupled problem, if you want to control the whole body of a humanoid.</p> <p>My third goal is to equip humanoids with semantic reasoning through foundation models. Frontier tech labs have been rapidly advancing the capabilities of large pre-trained models. I aim to design safe methods that are easily compatible with state-of-the-art models.</p> <p>My fourth goal is to test the deployment of safe humanoids in real use cases outside of lab environments. As part of the vibrant Munich robotics &amp; AI ecosystem, I’d like to foster regular interactions with other engineers and to advance collaborations between academia and industry.</p> <p>If you are interested in collaborating on any of these topics, please don’t hesitate to contact me via email or LinkedIn!</p> <p>Bonus goals:</p> <ul> <li>Algorithmic foundations of AI agents with neuroscience insights, e.g., continual learning with scalable brain-inspired architectures</li> <li>Mathematical theory of AI</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blogpost"/><category term="research"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>