<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://leomaglanoc.github.io/feed/blogs.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://leomaglanoc.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-12-17T11:12:28+00:00</updated><id>https://leomaglanoc.github.io/feed/blogs.xml</id><title type="html">blank | Blogs</title><subtitle>Leonardo Maglanoc&apos;s personal website on robotics, AI, and humanoid robots. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">My Research Goals</title><link href="https://leomaglanoc.github.io/blog/research-goals/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Research Goals"/><published>2025-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://leomaglanoc.github.io/blog/research-goals</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://leomaglanoc.github.io/blog/research-goals/"><![CDATA[ <p>In my <a href="/projects/foundation/">master’s thesis</a> in collaboration with Foundation, a humanoid robotics startup, I’m focusing on advancing language-guided multifingered manipulation with foundation models. My ultimate goal is to enable safe and reliable humanoid autonomy in human environments. My research goals can be roughly divided in three tracks:</p> <ul> <li>Goal 1: Safety and reliability guarantees through formal verification</li> <li>Goal 2: Problem extension to humanoid loco-manipulation</li> <li>Goal 3: Bridging the gap between academia and industry.</li> </ul> <p>My first goal is to provide reliability guarantees through formal verification of the safety and functionality of robotics systems. Ensuring safe robot autonomy in human environments is a critical issue, as failures such as collisions with humans would be catastrophic and must be prevented if we want to deploy robots in these environments.</p> <p>My second goal is to extend the problem setting from humanoid manipulation to loco-manipulation. Why? Because most real tasks require mobility of the autonomous system. And because locomotion and manipulation is inherently a coupled problem, if you want to control the whole body of a humanoid.</p> <p>My third goal is to bridge the gap between academia and industry, enabling the deployment of reliable and safe AI methods in industrial robotic systems. Being embedded in the Munich robotics ecosystem, for instance, through work experience at BMW or participation in industrial hackathons, I regularly engage with other roboticists, and I’d like to advance collaborations between academia and industry.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blogpost"/><category term="research"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>